var quiz = [{"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The MMPA has actually resulted in an increase in dolphin mortality."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Under the auspices of capitalism, fishers in the tuna industry failed to realize their own roles in sustaining their livelihoods."}, {"answers": ["political economy approach", "environmental ethics", "market environmentalism", "ecocentrism"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "The use of dolphin-safe labels is an example of which approach to solve environmental problems?"}, {"answers": ["pole and line fishing", "purse-seine fishing", "tuna ranching", "long-line fishing"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "Which type of fishing method is responsible for the death of over 100,000 albatrosses each year?"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "The ecological ethic is not opposed to the killing of individual animals as long as the species is not threatened."}, {"answers": ["pole and line fishing", "purse-seine fishing", "long-line fishing", "tuna ranching"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Which type of fishing method involves using a net to encircle a school of fish, then drawing the bottom shut to confine the fish?"}, {"answers": ["tuna ranching", "purse-seine fishing", "long-line fishing", "pole and line fishing"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Which type of fishing method involves capturing and rearing young wild tuna for human consumption?"}, {"answers": ["claim ownership and control of fish stocks in distant parts of the ocean.", "decide whether foreign fishers may fish within 200 nautical miles of the country\u2019s coastline.", "decide whether foreign fishers can sell their product in certain locations within the country.", "decide where foreign-owned canning factories may be located."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "An exclusive economic zone allows a country to:"}, {"answers": ["purse-seine fishing", "tuna ranching", "pole and line fishing", "long-line fishing"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "Which type of fishing method uses up to 60 miles of fishing line that is dragged behind a ship with thousands of hooks?"}, {"answers": ["Prices for tuna have exceeded $700/lb.", "Annual catches number in the trillion of pounds per year.", "Tuna used to be considered unfit for humans and used in pet foods instead.", "Tuna often migrate over 6000 miles per season."], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "Which of the following is TRUE about the tuna industry?"}, {"answers": ["The World Trade Organization has deemed that the embargo on non-labeled tuna violates free trade agreements.", "The movement forced U.S. companies like StarKist, Bumblebee, and Chicken of the Sea to start using dolphin-safe practices.", "The move was a devastating blow to the U.S. tuna market.", "U.S. trade embargo banned foreign tuna because they couldn\u2019t prove they were using dolphin-safe practices."], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "Which of the following is NOT true as it relates to dolphin-safe labels?"}, {"answers": ["long-line fishing", "purse-seine fishing", "tuna ranching", "pole and line fishing"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "Which type of fishing method produces the lowest overall catch in comparison to the other methods?"}, {"answers": ["Social construction has painted dolphins as charismatic, similar to humans.", "Social construction has been influenced by popular shows like \u201cFlipper\u201d that showed dolphins as friends of humans.", "Social construction has painted fish as vicious creatures that deserve to be killed.", "Social construction projects the notion that fish are just food."], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "The fact that the vast majority of consumers care more about the welfare of dolphins over tuna is true for all of the following socially constructed reasons, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["Fordism", "the first contradiction of capitalism", "the second contradiction of capitalism", "post-Fordism"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "The yellowfin tuna industry is an example of _______ because its own success undermines the resource base upon which it depends."}, {"answers": ["A victory for dolphins, but unsustainable harvest of tuna continues.", "Switch to log-setting that has decreased dolphin kills, but has increased the bycatch kills of other marine species.", "The unintentional increase of dolphin kills as fishers use even more dangerous methods to maximize tuna catches.", "Has moved fisheries into other locations of the ocean, like the WTP, which has lead to exploitation in that area."], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "There have been many positive strides for dolphin rights through labeling efforts. Unfortunately, the gains have accompanied ecological defeats which include all of the following, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["Allows for the intentional death of dolphins as long as their populations remain above sustainable levels.", "Prohibits the killing or sale of marine mammals.", "Mandates a reduction in dolphin mortality to zero over time.", "Mandates that\u00a0 tuna fisheries be managed for \u201coptimum sustained populations\u201d."], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "All of the following are true about the Marine Mammal Protection Act (MMPA), EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "The consumer boycott and dolphin-safe tuna labeling effectively led to the sustainable harvest of tuna."}, {"answers": ["Atlantic halibut", "Atlantic cod", "Chilean sea bass", "Grouper"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Bluefin tuna are not the only overfished species in the ocean. This fish was officially closed off from commercial fishing in 1992 and has yet to show signs of rebounding:"}, {"answers": ["scores", "tough luck", "byproducts", "bycatch"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "The accidental harvest of non-targeted marine species is called what?"}, {"answers": ["animal rights", "sustainable tuna harvesting", "green consumerism", "U.S. tuna corporations"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Dolphin-safe labels are considered a success by the advocates of all of the following EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["This method is called \u201cdolphin-baiting\u201d", "Traditionally, this involved the use of the purse-seine method", "This method can only be used in the ETP", "In the past, this method resulted in the deaths of up to 550,000 dolphins a year"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "All of the following are true of locating yellowfin tuna by the presence of dolphins, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["TNCs subcontract all levels of production to maximize profit.", "Tuna companies, like StarKist, are now just brands.", "TNCs own all of the parts of production--from the fishing vessels to the processing plants.", "TNCs move factories to locations with cheaper labor."], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "The result of the tuna industry transitioning from a Fordist to a post-Fordist industry includes all of the following, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "In the tuna industry, improvements in the means of production led to degradation of the conditions of production."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Moral extensionism has been applied to tuna as much as to dolphins."}, {"answers": ["Green certification is available to anyone who practices sustainable methods of production.", "Green certification does not prevent environmental degradation.", "Green certification standards are the same everywhere.", "Green certification ensures the practice of sustainable production methods."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Which statement about green certification is TRUE?"}, {"answers": ["purse-seine fishing", "long-line fishing", "pole and line fishing", "tuna ranching"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Which type of fishing method has been most blamed for the unintentional death of dolphins?"}, {"answers": ["vertical integration of processes such that extraction, production, and exchange are carried out by the same company in one location", "preference for domestic rather than transnational corporations", "flexibility and impermanent locations for the processes of extraction, production, and exchange", "high wages, mass production, and mass consumption"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "Post-Fordist industries are characterized by:"}, {"answers": ["utilitarian ethic", "ecological ethic", "ecocentric ethic", "animal rights ethic"], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "The ethic that promotes the well-being of individual animals rather than a species is the"}, {"answers": ["Dolphin-safe labels on tuna products.", "Switching to salmon instead of tuna as the protein of choice for sushi.", "Passage of the Marine Mammal Protection Act (MMPA).", "Development of Medina panels."], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Which of the following is an example of green consumerism as related to tuna and dolphins?"}, {"answers": ["Insatiable demand for tuna can only be met because tuna has an infinite resource base.", "Tuna are too valuable for their own good.", "Their fate is tied into global geopolitical decisions.", "Tuna is readily available on the market, despite declining populations."], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "The puzzle of tuna includes all of the following, EXCEPT:"}]

quizCollection['13'] = quiz
